# JEREMY WANG

Software Engineer | Fullstack Android Developer | Entrepreneur

La http://jerwng.com 

wyjeremy@gmail.com 

737-222-9817 

https://aithub.com/ierbotron



# WHO AM I?

I can best describe myself as a doer with tenacious will power to solve problems and to get sh\*t done. Personally, I am very coachable and eager to learn. I played 3 years of college football so I always tackle challenges with focus, drive and a never give up attitude. Pun intended ©

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Founder & Developer, PepRally

🛗 Jan 2016 – ongoing

✓ Austin, TX

- PepRally is a social app dedicated to college students aimed to improve the student-life experience
- Taught myself Android programming and created this app from concept to launch within 8 months while working full time at NI
- Data mined every varsity player profile and photo from UT Austin's public html using Python scripts
- Designed push notification and instant messaging features using Google Firebase and Socket.IO communicating over a Node.js server
- Launched to the Google Play Store and got 20 users in the first 2 weeks

# **Software Engineer**, National Instruments

Aua 2015 – onaoina

✓ Austin, TX

- Cross platform C++ driver development while working across multiple groups and giant software repos
- Independently delivered features including DMA fifos, download to flash, thermal shutdown and power management support
- Developed features and tests for a distributed test system in Python

# **Software Engineer**, Intelligent Mechatronics Systems

Aug 2013 – Dec 2013

✓ Waterloo, ON

- Acquired working knowledge of MVC client-server web architecture and relational backend databases
- Fullstack web development using Java, JavaScript and HTML/CSS

## **Software Display Engineer**, zSpace

🗯 Jan 2013 – Apr 2013

✓ Sunnyvale, CA

- Designed an automated test system to measure LCD display performance at various viewing angles
- Embedded software development with Visual C# and ThorLabs API to control multiple motors and other peripherals using multithreading
- Implemented the automated test system to the production line and increased efficiency of the manual QA process

## **Software Test Engineer**, IGNIS Innovation

May 2012 - Aug 2012

✓ Waterloo, ON

- Designed a data parsing software tool in Visual C# using RegEx to parse through jumbled test result files
- Programmed board bring-up tests in C and Python

# **PROJECTS**

#### Pi-Connect 4

- Classic connect 4 game made into a multiplayer webapp on a Node.js server using PubNub for realtime communication between server and game clients
- Raspberry Pi also acts as a client controller to an LED matrix display board to display the game state

#### 2048 Game

- Popular block puzzle game remade using Python with PyGame and Javascript with jQuery
- Implemented an auto solver that can get to 512 consistently

# **SKILLS**

#### Languages:

Java, C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

#### **Tools/Frameworks:**

Git, DynamoDB, EC2/S3, Firebase, Socket.IO, PubNub, ¡Query, AngularJS, Bootstrap, Android Studio, Android SDK, WinDBG, Arduino/Raspberry Pi

## **Programming Concepts:**

OOP, Multiprocess/Multithread, Linux, OS Kernels, RTOS, Material Design

# **EDUCATION**

**BASc.** Mechatronics Engineering

U of Waterloo, Sept 2010 – Apr 2015

# **AWARDS**

Academic All-Canadian (Football)

CIS, Sept 2014

## **Undergraduate Student Research** Award

NSERC, Apr 2014